Ting Chung

Savannah, GA 31407 | 678-557-5088 | tchung682@gmail.com Github ting682 | blog https://dev.to/ting682. | https://tingchung.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in aircraft systems engineering. Possess strong skills in web application development and engineering that help technological companies drive efficient and reliable software development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, React, and systems engineering.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Small groups - Github | Demo

A Javascript/Rails API single page application that allows a user to submit bible study topics.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Leveraged asynchronous Javascript fetch requests to Rails API backend using postgreSQL database.
- Rails API outputs ActiveRecord objects via JSON serializer.
- Used object oriented Javascript classes to encapsulate behavior which results in separation of concerns design pattern.
- Implemented Quill rich text editor to allow users to submit photos and videos along with blog.

Prayer gathering - Github | Demo

A Ruby on Rails web application that allows a user to host prayer gathering events.

- Utilized model-view-controller design pattern resulting in separation of concerns.
- Validated login and event data by creating Rails validation models to ensure persisted data validity.
- Established ActiveRecord many-to-many associations to create join table resulting in object relational mapping of data persisted to postgreSQL database.
- Encrypted user login data persisting salted and hashed password in postgreSQL database.

Prayer journal - Github | Demo

A Sinatra web application using ruby that allows a user to create prayer journal entries and submit prayers to the prayer wall.

- Persisted user's journal entries using ActiveRecord one-to-many associations to postgreSQL database.
- Allows users to signup and login to the web application.
- Utilized model-view-controller design pattern for object relational mapping.
- Encrypted user login data persisting salted and hashed password in postgreSQL database.
- Used ActiveRecord model to validate user and journal entry data.

EXPERIENCE

Gulfstream Aerospace Corporation

05/2012 - 05/2020

Technical Specialist I

- Implemented electrical design solutions for brakes, landing gear, hydraulics, and door systems.
- Investigated and resolved flight test and lab issues through troubleshooting and integration testing.
- Developed brake control system requirements for validation and verification of systems.

Gulfstream Aerospace Corporation

Savannah, GA

Savannah, GA

Service Center Coordinator

09/2010 - 05/2012

- Managed international business jet aircraft maintenance visits and aircraft export by ensuring strict project timelines were met.
- Provided maintenance solutions to adhere to rigorous repair station standards.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Online

Full Stack Web Development program

06/2020 - Present

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA 08/2007

Bachelor's of Science (BS) in Electrical Engineering